PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Ricardo Maqueda Martinez

Mobile Number: +44 7596 336330

Email: rinconestolmo@gmail.com
Place and date of birth: Madrid, Spain. May 20th, 1976

SUMMARY

My professional skills had been centred about system administration during more than 10 years, especially in storage area and backup for bank and telecommunications sectors. I master cloud computing with AWS, Azure and third-party backend like Parse and Firebase.

Ever since I met the mobile development world (more specifically iOS), I haven't stopped doing courses and in my free time, I used to develop small projects. By this way came my new professional profile: in 2013, I started to work as iOS freelance developer.

I am passionate about learn every day, trying to make code with the highest quality and have fun with my work.

I have a lot of repositories, many of them privates in Bitbucket and GitHub but I have one project as reference. This project was a test to access of one of my job. In this project apply techniques that I am learning. It's integrated with Sonar Cloud and Travis. Can be clone in: https://github.com/rmaqueda/OpenWeather

You can find more information about me in my LinkedIn page: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardomaqueda

SKILLS

Mobile App Develop

iOS develop with Objective-C	since 2013
Deploy App Store	since 2013
iOS develop with Swift	since 2016
Securing mobile applications	since 2016
Securing mobile application with Arxan	since 2017
Reactive RX-Swift and Combine	since 2019
macOS develop with Swift	since 2019

Methodology

Agile methodologies	since 2010
Jira	since 2010
Continues integration Jenkins	since 2010
Continues integration Bamboo	since 2012

System Administration

Backup and Storage administration	since 2004
Unix system administration	since 2004
Operating System virtualization	since 2010

23 July 2020 Page 1 of 5

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS Developer TUI Group

December 2018 - Present

I'm working delivering the iOS version of TUI app for several countries across Europe in 12 iOS developers' team. I mainly highlight these tools or technologies:

- Swift 5.1 is the main language but some legacy areas still in Objective-C.
- VIPER and MVVM are the mainly architectures on projects, more than 120K lines of code.
- I am using complex Core-Data scheme to persist the information and support offline mode.
- The tests coverage is above 40%
- I am using Jenkins, Buddybuild, Fastlane and Sonar Cloud.
- The team use Scrum and the common tools Jira and Confluence.

iOS Developer

Santander UK Technology

September 2017 - December 2018 (19 months)

Member of the Santander Wallet team, I delivered the iOS version of the official Santander Wallet application. On a day to day basis I was working with Scrum methodology, mentor junior developers, participate in code reviews. I mainly highlight these tools or technologies:

- All the new projects starting with Swift, but supporting old projects in Objective-C.
- Mainly focus in Wallet app but I was working in different Santander Projects.
- I acquired in Santander high knowledge about securing mobile application using tools like Arxan and develop native libraries for: encryption, jailbreak detection, obfuscation, SSL pinning, etc.
- I was actively collaborating with the security team and I was doing security pen-testing and ethical hacking in the main applications of the bank.

iOS Developer

Contractor & Miotek

January 2016 - August 2017 (10 month)

Develop native iOS and backend micro-services for mobile apps with NodeJS.

I deployed cost effective platforms on several cloud providers.

I was working whit different companies like: Metro Madrid, Optimiza Process, Norma4, Cognicase Management, Galleon Software. I mainly highlight these tools or technologies:

- Using 100% Swift projects.
- Using new technologies at the moment like NFC, to read custom NFC stickers.
- Deploy and support the backend as a service Parse in AWS supporting iOS and Android.
- Complete redesign of the Madrid Tube official app.

iOS Developer Telefónica I+D

May 2015 - January 2016 (9 month)

I collaborated in the international Movistar TV iOS app, has been already marketed in 8 countries. I mainly highlight these tools or technologies:

- All the projects in this period was develop in Objective-C.
- The unit test coverage exceeds the 80%.
- We used Jenkins for continues integration and auto deploy in Apple Store.

23 July 2020 Page 2 of 5

iOS Developer BBVA Bank

October 2014 - May 2015 (8 month)

I was working as iOS developer doing corporate applications to management parking areas and book meeting rooms.

The Parking App was awarded as the most valued internal application by BBVA employees.

I used agile methodologies and tools like Jira and Crucible (code-review tool) as well as Bamboo to automate run test, generate binary and distributed binaries to QA and store.

iOS Developer Contractor

January 2014 - October 2014 (10 month)

Develop native iOS.

Develop backend for mobile apps with NodeJS.

Deploy cost effective platforms on several cloud providers.

I was working whit different companies: Metro Madrid, Optimiza Process, Norma4, Cognicase Management, Galleon Software.

(I have omitted all non-iOS Developer jobs. Please, let me know if you need a full version)

23 July 2020 Page 3 of 5

EDUCATION

Industrial Electrics.

Polytechnics San Blas. Finished in 2000.

SUPPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

Design Patterns Escuela.it

40 hours

Analysis and Design Object-oriented programming Escuela.it

10 hours

Mantle, AFNetworking, Bolts and Core Data Keepcoding.es

20 hours

Ironhack, iOS Mobile Development Bootcamp IronHack.com

400 hours

Test Driven Development (TDD) iOS Keepcoding.es

40 hours

iOS de Intermediate Keepcoding.es

24 hours

iPhone & iPad Foundations Keepcoding.es

70 hours

Backends for Mobile Apps AGBO

36 hours

Core Graphics & Core Animation AGBO

24 hours

Design for Developers AGBO

40 hours

Symmetrix Performance Workshop EMC Education

Jun 2009. 32 hours

Symmetrix Business Continuity - TimeFinder Solutions EMC Education

March 2009. 16 hours

CLARiiON Host Integration & Management EMC Education

December 2008. 24 hours

Control Centre Management EMC Education

September 2008. 40 hours

IBM Tivoli Storage Manager IBM Training Services

December 2007. 40 hours

HP Enterprise Virtual Array (EVA)

HP Training services

August 2005. 45 hours

Brocade 12000 Switch Administration Oracle

March 2005. 16 hours

23 July 2020 Page 4 of 5

SUPPLEMENTARY EDUCATION (continued)

Unix Shell Script Programming

Shells: KSH, Bash, Bourne, Shell C

Polar internal training

TCP- IP in LINUX Red Hat

IBM

April 2002. 35 hours

IBM AIX Systems administration

IBM

April 2002. 35 hours

Information security

IBM

February 2002. 40 hours

SUN Solaris 8, System Administration

Oracle

SUN Solaris 8 Admin I, SUN Solaris 8 Admin II

November 2001. 80 hours

MCSE. Microsoft Certified System Engineer

Microsoft

Engineering Microsoft Certified Systems. Certificate 9 modules 1999-2000. 360 hours

Comunidad de Madrid

Hardware Personal Computers 1997. 12 months

ICE Formación

Microprocessors and Robotics 1995. 600 hours

LANGUAGE

Spanish

Native language

English

Before I moved to England I have studied for three years in British Council official languages school. Level B2. Since 2017, I am working in 100% English environment.

23 July 2020 Page 5 of 5